Megersa Muleta

Software Developer

Talented and industrious software developer with over 5 years of experience in overseeing the development of the most cutting edge IT solutions and applications. Eager to join the challenging work environment of your company to utilize my technical skills in creating responsive, user-friendly, and customer-oriented projects.

Email: megersabmuleta01@gmail.com Address: Gullale, Addis Ababa Phone: +251966916168

Experience

May 2023 - Present

Software Engineer

Elkas Technologies Kitchener, Ontario, Canada

- · Assigned as a MERN stack developer.
- · Working with applications with JAVA, NodeJs, ReactJs, SQL Server, No SQL as well as worked in troubleshooting methods and documented solutions.
- · Performed all testing and troubleshooting methods and documented resolutions in the system

Dec 2022 - Mar 2023

Software Developer Internship

Awash Bank Addis Ababa

- Built modern applications using MySQL, Java, SQL server, and Spring and supported the company's development and testing processes
- · Developing and maintaining web applications using AngularJs, spring boot and other related technologies.
- · Collaborating with cross-functional teams including designers, product managers, and other developers to create high-quality products.
- · Implementing responsive design and ensuring cross-browser compatibility.
- · Participating in code reviews and providing constructive feedback to other developers.

Feb 2021 - Dec 2022

Junior Software Developer

Nuhik Engineering Saris, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia

- · Developed effective microservices and web services and created a series of unit tests to ensure that the projects passed all quality benchmarks
- · Worked with a team of expert coders to write maintainable code and maintain existing software to improve performance and fix bugs
- Performed testing and troubleshooting of systems as required by the Software Development supervisor
- · Consulted with clients to identify their projects specifications and follow up with deployed applications status and any technical issues

Education

2019 - Present

Computer Engineering

Microlink IT College Piasa STt. george street, Addis Ababa

Languages

English

Advanced

Oromiffa

Native

Skills

development

ReactJS Spring boot full Stack

MySQL gitHub & Git python

Agile methodology MERN Wordpress

googleCloud

Megersa Muleta

Software Developer

Email: megersabmuleta01@gmail.com

Address: Gullale, Addis Ababa **Phone:** +251966916168

Projects

Portfolio Site:

• its my portfolio site that i have been developed using React JS and it shows my previous work history and experiences of languages, also you can contact me through it.

Link: https://megersam.netlify.app

E-commerce:

MERN stack based e-commerce website, a fully-functional online store that allows customers to browse, search, and
purchase products. The MERN stack includes four key technologies: MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, and Node.js, which work
together seamlessly to create a powerful web application.

Link: https://github.com/megersam/-ecommerce

Airbnb Clone:

This is a Full Stack Airbnb clone repository using Next.js 13 App Router, React, Tailwind, Prisma, MongoDB, and NextAuth. It
has features such as Tailwind design, credential authentication, image upload using Cloudinary CDN, and advanced search
algorithm. It also has a booking/reservation system, favorites system, and shareable URL filters. Additionally, it includes
instructions on how to handle server error and loading states, create and delete properties, and handle relations between
server and child components..

Link: https://github.com/megersam/airbnb-clone

Hotel booking UI React Js:

• Web application that enables users to search and book Hotels Online, view estimated fees ranges for places, and locate available rooms based on their search location.

<u>Link:</u> https://github.com/megersam/hotelbookingMERN

React Js Admin Dashboard:

• React.js admin dashboard a versatile and powerful tool that can be used across a range of industries, including e-commerce, social media, and more. It provides a centralized platform for managing various aspects of your business, such as user accounts, product listings, orders, and customer support.

Link: https://github.com/megersam/reactJSDashboard

https://dashboard-shoppy.netlify.app/